let's look at the solution to our MSI
access quiz we have two cores with
private caches and MSI coherence
initially block X is in memory which
means that it's really invalid in both
of the caches after we read X in C once
cache see one's cache will transition
this block from I to s the shared state
because this was a read we move to the
shared state even though it is not
really shared this is our way of saying
basically that the block is clean and
that we only want to read it in c2s
cache it stays invalid when c2 then does
a read it also gets the Block in the
shared state and if we snoop a read
request in the shared State we stay in
the shared state so finally when c1
writes to X because it has the Block in
the shared state it needs to send an
invalidation out that results in c2
moving the block to the invalid state it
can no longer be read until we get the
new copy from C 1 and C 1 after writing
has the Block in the modified State